Every life is a work of art.
And it becomes complete
when all the pieces come together.
Why did you get up? Go back to bed.
Mom.
You know what? I made a new friend today,
and he has the same name.
I'm tired.
I told you to sleep first
since I come home late.
My life couldn't be complete
because of a piece I've never had before.
I couldn't see why though.
Listen to your teacher, okay?
Let's go!
Hey!
Mom, he's my friend Ji-ung.
- I see.
- Hi.
Hi, are you Ji-ung?
I'm Ung's mom.
- A piece everyone has…
- Nice to meet you, ma'am.
You look so bright.
Thank you for being Ung's friend.
- …and isn't that hard to obtain.
- Hold hands with your friend on your way.
I didn't know why I was the only one
who didn't have that piece.
Here you go.
All right.
Let's see.
Here.
Are you eating alone again?
Here you go. Put the bowl outside
when you're done.
The memories I have of my childhood…
…are of being alone…
or being with a friend who was alone.
And she was also there a few times.
That was it.
And when time passed…
and I grew old enough
to remember everything,
I became numb to a lot of things.
But that doesn't mean
that I got used to everything.
And around that time…
You don't have a dad either?
No. You don't either?
Then do you live with your mom?
Yes.
It must have been tough for you.
Why would it be tough for me?
My mom's the one who suffered.
She had a fever last night,
so I told her not to go to work.
But she never listens to me.
She makes a huge fuss whenever
I get sick, though.
You two must be close.
How can we not be?
All we have is each other.
Anyway, I told our homeroom teacher
that I'm going home early,
so tell the other teachers for me.
We have exams tomorrow though.
My mom will yell if she hears
I came home because she was sick,
but she'll secretly be pleased.
She can't live without me.
- I'll get going, then.
- Okay.
So I got curious.
I wanted to know the reason why I couldn't
have that piece.
Mom, can you…
Can you live without me?
Why are we living like this?
Why do we have to pretend like we hate--
Without you…
I wouldn't be living like this.
I wouldn't be living…
such a pathetic life.
That's when I realized…
that I was a useless piece in her life.
The thing I wanted so desperately
was hell for her.
So I decided that
I would never have that piece.
My life wasn't a work of art.
It was just an episode
of a boring documentary series
that no one watches.
EPISODE 15
THREE IDIOTS
Yes, I went to the gallery
to check something.
I'm heading back now.
Go inside and get some rest.
I'll be home soon. It's cold outside.
All right.
Let's not give each other presents.
The culture of giving gifts
on anniversaries
just makes people spend money.
It's what's on the inside that counts.
I think spending money
on gifts is meaningless.
But back then,
I only said that because
I didn't want to take up your time.
So you actually wanted me
to come pick you up.
Yes.
May I help you?
Oh, yes.
Are you buying a gift for your girlfriend?
Yes.
What kind of style does she like?
Well, she's really pretty.
I see…
I mean, what style of clothes
or accessories does she wear?
Right…
Neat and tidy?
I see. Neat and tidy.
What are you doing?
Putting a bell on a cat.
The store was having a huge sale.
They said I should get one.
But I thought it would look better
on you than me.
It's pretty.
What?
Thanks.
I paid full price for it
and it took me an hour to pick.
I got you earrings too.
Try these on.
- Do you like them?
- Yes.
Should we
hang out at home all day
instead of going out?
Yes.
You know that's what I'm best at.
A MIDSUMMER NIGHT'S DREAM
You're done reading already?
Why did you make so much?
Right. I made more than I thought.
How will we finish this?
We can.
It looks good, right?
It looks tasty.
I'm so full.
Me too. I'm so full.
Look.
Look at my stomach.
- Are you okay?
- Yes.
Let's decide who does the dishes.
- Rock, paper, scissors.
I'm not done yet.
Are you done?
All right.
One, two, three.
Why are you laughing?
Jjongjjong looks so ugly!
No, he looks adorable!
Hey!
I'm not doing this.
Hey, these are expensive!
Darn it.
Let's not watch a documentary.
Why? I wanted to watch this.
Aren't you sick of them?
- What do you want to watch?
- Let's see what's on.
That one!
SHOP FOR LUXURY ITEMS ON
TREN:BE
HOT ITEMS THIS WINTER
It's cold now.
I should get a scarf.
This one.
BUY NOW, SHOPPING CART
- What are you doing?
- What?
Nothing.
Come to think of it,
you took a shower here last time too.
This is still a guy's house.
So? It's your house.
We weren't even dating back then.
That's an enthusiastic greeting.
Oh, when we said we'd be friends?
You're not doing that
at all of your friends' homes, are you?
Why aren't you answering?
I did that to seduce you.
You're such a cunning desert fox.
Hey, you're just supposed to say "fox."
That sounds worse for some reason.
You've changed, Yeon-su.
- Dry my hair for me.
- What?
Dry my hair.
Hey, can't you even dry your own hair?
How could you…
My goodness.
All dried, ma'am.
Thank you. My right ear is hot, though.
But your hair is perfectly dry.
You're not going to keep asking me
to do this for you, are you?
Keep doing it for me.
My gosh. How are you going
to live without me?
Jeez.
You're acting strange again.
What are you trying to do now?
It's so peaceful.
See? It's nice to not be fighting.
What goes through your mind
when things are like this?
Well…
Not much.
Just "This is nice." Stuff like that.
Whenever I feel this happy,
I get anxious.
Why?
I get worried
that I'll ruin everything again.
That won't happen. Don't worry.
Yeon-su.
No. I'll tell you next time.
ENROLLMENT GUIDE
SCHOOL OF ARCHITECTURE
Why did you order so much stuff?
But why are they all women's…
Are these all for Yeon-su?
I don't think I ordered that many.
You're trying so hard
to look like a sweet boyfriend.
Do you really think she'll be happy
when she receives all this?
She likes gifts more than I thought.
Too many gifts will be overwhelming.
You're so clueless, Ung.
There's one for you.
Where? What is it?
I see.
This?
It's a bit smaller than the others,
but thanks.
Right, Ung. We got the brochure. Ta-da!
It looks good, doesn't it?
It's finally tonight. Are you ready, Ung?
We'll be making history
with a night exhibition.
Is Yeon-su coming today?
- She's coming on the last day.
- Why?
There will be journalists,
and a lot of people will recognize us
because of the documentary.
I'm okay with it, but she said
she doesn't want to steal the spotlight.
Yeon-su is so mature.
She's so thoughtful.
What could this be?
Why won't it open?
- Eun-ho.
- Yes?
I need to tell you something
when the exhibit's over.
What is it? Just tell me now.
I'll tell you after the exhibit ends.
All right.
But why can't I get the tape off?
Do you have long nails?
Can you open this for me?
What is it though?
I don't remember.
There was a special sale or something.
Six, five, four, three, two…
Sol-i!
What do I do with you?
What are you doing after work?
Why? Why do you want to know…
what I'm doing?
What? Well, it's Ung's exhibit.
Come if you're not busy.
It'll be late at night,
so you can come after work.
Will you be there?
Of course. I'm his manager.
Right. Of course.
You're being so obvious, Eun-ho.
What?
Are you coming or not?
Do you want a ticket?
Sure. Leave it here.
Why are you acting so strange?
Are you sick?
No, why?
Why are your eyes like this?
Anyway, I should get going.
And tell me in advance if you're coming.
It'll run for three days.
Bye.
See you.
Having a crush is terribly painful.
I know it so well.
You poor boy.
GO-OH'S EXHIBITION,
WHILE THE CITY SLEEPS, OPENS
IT WILL BE A NIGHT-TIME EXHIBIT
- I'm not going.
- What?
Where? Are you trying
to bail on another schedule?
No, it's not that.
Jeez, you startled me.
I'm always so anxious these days
because of you.
Right, you have the shoot
for the documentary this weekend.
It's taking longer than I thought.
It's the last episode.
I'll give you the script later.
- Chi-seong.
- Yes?
- I'm sorry.
- What? Why?
Sorry about what?
What are you thinking of doing?
No, it's not for what I'm going to do.
I'm sorry for what I did.
I acted impulsively.
Couldn't you say that first?
You startled me
by apologizing out of the blue.
I won't startle you anymore.
What's gotten into you?
This is making me more nervous.
I'm going to do my best
to live a normal life now.
Right.
I take back my promise not to startle you.
- I'll give you a couple more shocks.
- Can't you just tell me in advance?
So I can take some calming pills.
Hey.
What are you doing?
Is Mr. Kim inside?
Hasn't he said
anything about thanking me yet?
He must be grateful
after seeing the ratings.
I don't think he's in a situation
to do that right now.
Why? I'm sure he's not busy.
I heard he finished editing everything.
What's with him? Did someone die?
I don't know. He's not even
going home these days.
He acted like that before,
but it seems pretty serious this time.
He's becoming more and more like Dong-il.
Mr. Park?
Yes. He's acting exactly like him
when he's out of it.
Mr. Park isn't like that though.
Don't even get me started.
He's worse than him at times.
He stays cooped up in the editing room
whenever something happens.
Let's go. Leave him be.
Why don't we get some coffee?
We should give him some alone time.
Come on.
Come on, let's go.
Okay.
They say
I'm going to die.
I'm going to die soon.
So…
please film me before I do.
Please do that.
- Thanks, Chae-ran.
- That's for Ji-ung.
Why would you give coffee
to someone who uses all our electricity?
Don't you feel sorry for him?
He's been in there for days.
I feel sorry for myself
for having him on my team.
See you. Thanks for this.
Mr. Park is definitely
not the kind of person you said.
Even if he doesn't act like it,
he cares about Mr. Kim dearly.
He cares about him a lot.
I've never seen him do that though.
Do you know why Mr. Kim never quit
when he was an assistant producer?
NEW NOYANGPO FISH MARKET
FIGHT AGAINST FORCED DEMOLITION
WE'RE JOINING THE FIGHT
PROTECT OUR MARKET
THE FISH MARKET IS OUR HOME
Why did you bring such a useless kid here?
ASSISTANT PRODUCER KIM JI-UNG
Do I have to keep working
with this stupid kid?
- Mr. Park! Where are you?
- Yes?
What is it?
Don't take your anger out on him.
Come on, let's work together.
We've been waiting for hours.
He's the assistant producer,
but he's not doing anything.
Are we going to shoot all night?
Don't you see we're all working hard?
I told you I have to end early today!
It's my wedding anniversary!
I've never been able to go home
on my anniversaries.
My wife might divorce me.
What are you going to do about that?
I'll beg her to forgive you.
Let's take a break.
We should all eat something.
Go and buy some ramyeon.
If we had a smart assistant,
we would have ended early.
What's the matter with you?
We wasted the whole day!
- Let's go for a smoke. Come on.
- Jeez.
It's all my fault.
Jeez.
Is this a late-night snack or breakfast?
- Is it done?
- Yes, you can eat now.
Here you go.
- What's this?
- They gave me some.
It's clean, so it's okay.
You should have gotten some crab
or squid instead.
This is going to ruin the taste.
You should eat seaweed on your birthday.
Here you go.
Is it your birthday?
Hey, what's all this?
What lunatic would put seaweed in ramyeon?
- Just eat it.
- I'll pour it.
It's fine. Give me your bowl.
Eat up before it gets soggy.
- Here.
- Eat up.
Give me some too.
Hey, happy birthday.
Eat up.
Thank you.
Here.
They talk about the new market
and how there are protests
on the news, but look.
People are still
just living their daily lives.
Our job is to record things like this.
Things that people miss
because it seems so ordinary.
People who live their ordinary lives
and our daily lives as well.
If we put them together,
they become stories about life.
Don't be fooled.
Run away while you're still young.
Don't mess this up.
I have to convince him to stay!
You're coming to work tomorrow, right?
Eat up.
What is it?
- Putting seaweed in ramyeon…
- What about it?
Ji-ung did that for me
when I was an assistant too.
What?
Did you fall for that too?
Mr. Kim, that sly fox.
He used that to keep you here.
I knew it. The documentary team
is much more fun than the drama team.
WHILE THE CITY SLEEPS
GO-OH SOLO EXHIBIT
EXHIBITION HOURS
You may go in.
Welcome.
Enjoy the exhibit.
Thank you for coming.
Welcome.
Enjoy the exhibit.
LEADERSHIP TRAINING CO-OP SEMINAR
GO-OH'S SOLO EXHIBITION A SUCCESS
You're very impressive, Ung.
UNG
Hey.
Did you get off work?
Yes, I'm heading home now.
I saw the article.
You look really nice today.
There are more people than I expected.
I'm a bit nervous.
You did well at the drawing show
despite the crowd.
You seemed to enjoy the attention.
Gosh, I just want to finish this quickly
and stay home with you.
Ung!
I should get going.
You're coming on the last day, right?
Yes. I'll give you
the most enthusiastic congratulations.
I miss you, Yeon-su.
Bye.
Do you have regular working hours?
How many hours do you work a day?
It differs depending
on the building's size and shape,
but I work
around 12 hours a day on average.
It's something
I can draw with a lot of detail.
The height I prefer the most is 35 feet.
- Congratulations.
- Thank you.
- Hello.
I'm a little nervous.
Hello.
Please check the routes
the customers take.
- All right.
- If you come this way,
I'll show you
where they'll hold the book talk.
We'll do the book talk here.
Send me the seating arrangements.
And the author prefers communicating
with people close up,
- so I think a circle would be good.
- All right.
And I updated the location
for the drama shoot, so share that.
- Okay.
Let's do the seats in a circle.
You all know it's the last day
of Go-oh's exhibit, right?
- Did you all get tickets?
- I went last night with my girlfriend.
- It was so nice.
- Really?
Lucky you.
I would have gone
if I had a girlfriend too.
Is Ye-in busy? She probably
doesn't have anyone to go with.
I should go with her.
I thought you were a ghost!
Why are you looking at me like that?
Well, it seems like
you've changed a lot recently.
You seem a bit warmer,
not that you were cold or anything.
You even joined us
for the gathering last time.
You seem to be in a good mood these days.
- Right? She looks really happy.
- Yes.
- So…
- You're dating someone, right?
Who is it?
What are you trying to say?
We're just curious what kind of person
changed you like this.
And whether it's someone we know.
We were wondering if it's Mr. Jang.
We just wanted to know
how cool of a guy he is.
Well, this is about my private life.
Let's only talk about work.
- Right.
- Yes, of course.
I'll meet the staff and finish up here.
- Okay.
- Yes.
- And Myeong-ho.
- Yes?
- Come with Ye-in later.
- Where?
To my boyfriend's exhibit.
You'll regret it if you don't come
since it's the last day.
Boyfriend?
Go-oh?
Ji-ung. You've got to stop.
Should I stop eating?
That's not what I'm talking about.
Stop what, then?
Moping around like that.
Sit down.
And "moping"?
Is that a way to talk to your superior?
I was just going to leave you be,
but you're going too far.
I know you're having a hard time
because you're heartbroken,
but it's not something to brood over
for this long. You're a grown-up.
Right, I was rejected too.
Thanks for rubbing it in.
That really hurts.
Weren't you acting like this
because of Ms. Kook?
You shouldn't mention names like that.
Then why aren't you going home?
Because I don't want to go home.
Why?
Just because.
Did something happen?
Are you interrogating me?
You're Mr. Park's spy, aren't you?
You're making me worried.
I get that you tend to
push yourself when you work,
but you're doing work
that you don't even have to do.
You're the one who told me
not to make a habit of working overnight.
So why aren't you going home?
Thanks for worrying about me.
But don't get so upset.
People are saying
you're starting to act like me.
Then you should take care of yourself
so I won't worry.
All right, fine.
I can't even work late anymore
because of your nagging.
It's not that--
Just eat. It'll get cold.
Yes?
Yes. What is it?
The way you look at me
makes me pretty sad.
No, I was just startled.
I didn't expect you to come.
Thanks for coming.
Don't be ridiculous.
I got a formal invitation.
You asked me to come.
What? You didn't send this?
My gosh.
I didn't think I'd become so pathetic.
No, I did send it.
Right?
I was living a busy life
and I totally forgot about you.
But I came because you asked.
Were you
waiting for someone?
Oh, I guess she's a bit late.
Ms. Kook Yeon-su?
She's still not here?
Your girlfriend's totally neglecting you.
If you had dated me, this wouldn't happen…
Hey, that was a joke. You should smile.
These flowers are so pretty. Thank you.
I'm always the one giving you flowers.
I was used to accepting them all the time.
Your drawings are still really nice.
Were there a lot of people?
There were a lot before you came,
but there aren't any now.
Maybe it's too late at night.
Oh, I bought the tickets for this hour.
What?
I bought all the tickets.
They say there are two ways
to make friends.
Spend a lot of time with them,
or make an impression.
But for me, making an impression
is faster than spending time with them.
You were touched, right?
I know. Well, then…
Let's be friends. For real this time.
You're more unusual than I thought.
Someone told me that
if I want to live a normal life,
I can just pretend to.
So I'm going to make friends
like a normal person.
This isn't normal at all though.
Anyway…
are you going to leave me hanging?
Oh, sorry.
Do you…
give discounts to your friends?
Of course.
Our editing room ghost is finally leaving!
Round of applause!
Come on, clap.
Go home. I hope I never see you again.
I get treated so badly
even if I work so hard.
You don't have to work so hard,
so sleep at home, all right?
Your water and electricity
will get cut soon.
Don't exaggerate.
Ji-ung.
How about we go out for some drinks?
- No.
- I knew it. Get lost.
I'm sick of staying here with you.
I'll drink with…
Hey, where did he go?
Mr. Park.
You should go home too.
It's scary. Nobody's home.
- Bye.
- Ji-ung.
Is something up?
No.
Is Yeon-su still not here?
We have to close soon.
- No.
- Should I start wrapping up?
Okay.
You're so strange. How could you think
of doing an exhibit at this hour?
I enjoyed your exhibit.
They're still good,
but there's still no advancement.
Did you come here to say that?
Jeez.
Stop following me around.
Did you sell some drawings?
I have no time for you. Just go.
You can read it on the news
that you love so much.
You're so annoying.
You never said anything
about the plagiarism though.
Yes. I'm not interested.
I'll leave then.
What makes you think you're all that?
Do you feel like your life is
all elegant and special
if you ignore everything?
What?
I stole your drawing.
Hey, Tae-seon.
Did you decide what to hand in?
Are you finished?
Yes, I did.
Hey, this is awesome.
But this seems
a bit similar to Ung's drawings.
Really?
Hey, Ung. Do you think so too?
Let me see yours. Wouldn't it be
bad if they're too similar?
I can draw a new one.
A new one? The deadline's tomorrow!
If I'm late, too bad.
What makes you think you're so special
even back then and now?
That's funny.
Is that really something
you should be asking me?
That face again.
That mocking look.
Why? Do you need more attention?
You pretend
not to be interested in anything.
Well…
things must have seemed easy
for you since you had everything.
But still, you shouldn't have been
so obvious about it.
That makes the people around you
trying their best lose their spirit.
It's really annoying.
So the best you could do
was copy my drawings?
I was curious
how you'd react
after getting something of yours stolen.
But…
seeing that you
still had that look on your face…
made me pity you.
What?
It seemed like
your life was so meaningless
that you could abandon anything.
What would be left of your life
if you lived like that?
I really can't stand to hear this.
You don't have the right
to talk to him like that, you thief.
I knew it. You admitted it yourself
that you plagiarized him.
I'm going to tell all the reporters
about this. You just wait and see.
Your drawings are actually pretty boring.
They're all empty.
Why are you still here?
You should go see Ung.
Didn't you hear the doctor?
I'm fine.
Go on.
I'm going to get some more sleep.
My goodness.
You get hospitalized
once in a while at this age.
It's no big deal, so go on.
You're doing this on purpose.
Yeon-su.
You're going to leave me.
You're…
getting ready to leave me.
Listen to me carefully, Yeon-su.
You know how tough I am.
I'm going to live a long life.
Even if the grim reaper comes for me,
I'm going to hold on and stay here.
I'm just…
scared…
that maybe, just maybe…
I might end up leaving you all alone.
Don't say that, Grandma.
I can't live without you.
You need to.
You have to live even without me.
You have to eat well
and do everything you want to do.
You must.
But do you know what I think
when I look at you?
That I'm being punished
by having you live like me.
All I need is you, Grandma.
And all you need is me.
- We've lived happily together--
- All I need is you.
Because all I have left is to grow older.
You're the only one I need.
But you…
Don't live like me.
Keep people close to you,
do things that you want to do,
and enjoy your life.
Don't live just for me, Yeon-su.
That way
I won't be ashamed to face
your parents when I leave.
Oh, hey! Gu Eun-ho!
Hey, Sol-i.
Where are you going?
Is the exhibit over?
Yes. Did you close the bar?
Yes.
Right.
What's with that face?
Shouldn't you be throwing a party
to celebrate the end of the exhibit?
- I'm not in the mood.
- Why?
But where's Ung? Why are you alone?
The person you have called…
Where are you?
I respect you for trying to drink
when you can't handle your alcohol.
How economical.
Are you drunk after drinking this little?
I'm fine.
You've picked up bad drinking habits.
Should I match your level of drunkenness?
I'll catch up if I drink all this.
- Don't act so tough.
- What? You don't believe me?
- I'll show you.
- No, don't.
I didn't call you so you'd get drunk.
This is mine.
Don't be so cheap.
Hey.
It's been quite a while
since we drank together like this.
Right.
My exhibit was until today.
Why didn't you come?
I was busy.
That's a simple answer.
I'm actually pretty upset with you.
What about now?
Are you free?
I finished a week's worth of work
in advance.
The people around you will hate you
if you work so much like that.
Hey.
My mom's going to die.
But…
I don't feel sad at all.
How pitiful.
Who?
Just… Everyone.
Us…
and everyone.
Excuse me.
Do you need any help?
Who are you here to see?
Yeon-su!
What are you doing out here in the cold?
I…
I thought…
I ruined everything again.
What are you talking about?
How long have you been here?
I thought
I ruined everything again.
I'm sorry, Ung.
I'm sorry.
I told you that won't ever happen.
You're not going to ruin anything.
Ung.
Yes.
I'm in so much pain.
I…
I'm in so much pain right now.
Okay.
Why are you looking so down?
Didn't the exhibit end well?
It was a disaster.
What?
A famous critic criticized him harshly.
Why?
The drawings seemed cool.
What did they say?
Ung is going to need
a lot of comforting today.
HOW LONG WILL GO-OH
STAY TRAPPED IN HIS OWN WORLD?
GO-OH HAS HELD
AN INNOVATIVE NIGHT-TIME EXHIBITION
GO-OH DRAWS DETAILED
ILLUSTRATIONS OF BUILDINGS…
BUT THERE IS IMMATURITY
HIDDEN BEHIND HIS TECHNICAL PROWESS
"His drawings that show his emotions
are just like doodles
of a child trapped in his own world."
Let's go inside.
THREE IDIOTS
EPILOGUE
I want to go with you.
Subtitle translation by: Ju-young Park